A Guide to the Additional Papers of Douglas H. Gordon, 1934-1988
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Additional Papers of Douglas H. Gordon, 1934-1988
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10419-e
Ca. 25,000 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Shelved in remote storage. Users must request at least 24 hours in advance of desired use.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given to the Library by Mary L. Dierdorff through Jeanne Hammer, Library Development Office, University of Virginia, on June 26, 1997.
Biographical/Historical Information
Douglas Huntly Gordon (1902- ), lawyer and financier, of Charlecote House, Baltimore, Maryland, received his law degree from Harvard University in 1928 and was admitted to the Maryland bar in 1929. He was assistant United States district attorney for Maryland from 1934-1939. He was president of St. John's College, Annapolis, Maryland, 1931-1934; and, president of the Municipal Arts Society, Baltimore, Maryland, 1935-1970. Memberships included the American Bar Association, Decorated Legion of Honor, and Palmes Academiques in France. He was the author of legal and historical articles. Gordon was a collector of books, especially those of the French Renaissance, and of drawings, especially those of eighteenth and nineteenth century France. He married Winifred Macmillan Claude on June 2, 1934.
Scope and Content Information
The additional papers of Douglas H. Gordon consist of correspondence, papers, financial papers, photographs, and printed material pertaining to European travel. There are travel itineraries, 1946-1985; agendas for International Law Conferences, business correspondence and records; records and receipts for purchases of art and literature; also literary reviews, newsclippings, sheets from sales catalogues, museum catalogues, cards, and art prints. Also included are three manuscript binders of catalogues of the early and late French Books of the Charlecote House Library, vol. 1-3, and 16 photographs of Mr. and Mrs. Douglas H. Gordon, ca. 1934-1980. There is also personal correspondence from Winifred M. Gordon and other family members and letters pertaining to routine legal matters among the papers. Contained throughout are lists of names and addresses in Europe, particularly London, England; Paris, France; and Brussels, Belgium.
Organization
Material was removed from folders with brackets and then placed in folders in the same order as removed. Each set of papers for a specific year is chiefly filed in reverse chronological order.
Contents List
- European Travel 1937 (1945-1947), 2 folders (Box 1)
  [Letters of introduction from James Gustavus Whiteley (1866- ), H[erbert] C. de Roth, and J. H. Threadgill; photographs of La Breteche, Seine et Oise, France, crowd with King George VI (d.1952) in center at Canterbury, and [Canterbury] tower; correspondence about Gordon's article, "A Canterbury Pilgrimage"; R[obert] P[reston] Harriss (1902-1989), editor, Gardens, Houses and People; H[enry] I[rving] Brock (1876-1961), The New York Times; William de Krafft, Union League Club, New York; M[arland] Hamilton Whitman, editor, The Sun; Frits Lugt (1884-1970), Paris; Melville B[ell] Grosvenor (1901-1982), National Geographic Magazine; Marion [Ainsworth White?], Long Island; TMs, "A Canterbury Pilgrimage"; Harry A. Bull, editor, Town and Country; Madame Mary Toussaint, St. Cloud, France; Guy Lavaud (d. 1977), Poissy, France; Diana Mary Reynolds, Paris; Jean Barbey, Paris]
- European Travel 1947, 2 folders (Box 1)
  [Frits Lugt, Paris; Cottman Company; letters of introduction for French girl, Alice Doumic, and with Doumic; Albert Sergysels, Brussels; passport photos of Douglas H. Gordon; Paul J[oseph] Sachs (1878-1965), Harvard University, Cambridge, Massachusetts; Perrin C. Galpin (1889-1973), Belgian American Foundation, Inc., New York; E[arle] D[odds] Stevenson (1885-1956), The National Trust for Scotland, Edinburgh; Diana Mary Reynolds, Aldershot, England and snapshot (ca. 1947 August); Arthur Rau, Yorkshire and Union Society, Oxford; Winifred M. Gordon, Marlow Bucks, England and France; wedding invitation for Diana Mary Reynolds and H. Errington Brewis (1947 August); Georges Marin (1906- ), Brown's Hotel, London; Dorothy [Eugenia] Miner (1904-1973), Walters Art Gallery, Baltimore]
- European Travel 1947-1949, 3 folders (Box 1)
  [London dealers--P. & D. Colnaghi and Company, Ltd., Crichton Brothers; International Bar Association Conference at the Hague; Diane Mary Reynolds Brewis, Westcliff on Lea, England; Pierre Beres (1913- ), Paris; Lucien Scheler (1902- ), Paris; Lucien [Camille] Goldschmidt (1912-1992), Pierre Beres, Inc. Paris; Harry Goldgar (1920- ), Paris; Henry Falkenstein, New York; Frits Lugt, Paris; Edouard Tyberghein, Paris; A[rthur] E[wart] Popham (1889-1970), The British Museum, London; James Byam Shaw (1903- ), London; Lloyd A[rnold] Brown (1907-1966), Peabody Institute Library, Baltimore; program for the French Theatre National De L'Opera; letter of introduction from H[enry] R[ussell] H[itchcock](1903-1987), Middletown, Connecticut; George H[yde] Fallon (1902-1980), United States House of Representatives, re tax treaty between France and United States; program for Netherlands Institute for History of Art summer course]
- European Travel 1948-1950, 2 folders (Box 1)
  [London dealers--Bernard Quaritch Ltd., Craddock and Barnard, P. & D. Colnaghi and Company, Ltd.; Paris dealers--Arthur Rau, Maurice Gobin; Jacob Hirsch (1874-1955), New York; Sir Leigh Ashton (1897-1983, London; Lucien Scheler, Librairie Thomas-Scheler, Paris; John [Waynflete] Carter (1905-1975), Charles Scribner's Sons; James Byam Shaw, London; Osbert Lancaster (1908-1986), London; Ana Ricarda (1925- ), Brown's Hotel, London, re her ballet being put on by Grand Ballet de Monte Carlo; Jean Barbey, Paris; George Kent Bellows; Baltimore; Diana Reynolds Brewis, British Troops Austria; George Maurice Morris (1889-1954), Morris, KixMiller and Baar, Washington, D. C.; pamphlet, Netherlands Law Digest, by Dr. E. H. von Baumhauer; program for "Comedie Francaise"; French brochures]
- European Travel 1949-1951, 3 folders (Box 1)
  [London dealers--Maggs Bros., Ltd., P. & D. Colnaghi and Company, Ltd., Bernard Quaritch, Ltd.; Paris dealers - Arthur Rau, Fabius Freres; Pendleton Beckley, Paris; Jean Barbey, Paris; George H[yde] Fallon, United States House of Representatives; Elbridge Durbrow (1903- ), Department of State; John [Grey] Murray (1908-1993), London; Thomas D'Alesandro, Jr. (1903-1987), Mayor, Baltimore; Diana Mary Reynolds Brewis, British Troops Austria; Harold J[ohn] Gallagher (1894-1981), American Bar Association; passport photos of Douglas H. Gordon; Frank B[enedict] Ober, Ober, Williams, Grimes and Stinson, Baltimore; Henry F[ranklin] Butler (1896-1964), International Bar Association; International Bar Association; "Third International Conference of the Legal Profession, London, July, 1950"; Henry S. Miller (1901- ), Mead, Miller and Company, Baltimore]
- European Travel 1951 (Box 1)
  [Paris dealers--Maggs Brothers, Ltd., Arthur Rau; TMs, "Paris in Springtime"; program for "Les Heures Glorieuses de Paris"; Douglas McKay (1893-1959), Governor, Salem, Oregon; Jean Barbey, Paris; Norman C[ecil] Melvin (1916- ), Cook Ruzicka, Veazey and Grans, Baltimore, with draft of brief]
- European Travel 1952 (Box 1)
  [London dealers--Bernard Quaritch, Ltd., Crichton Brothers, Maggs Brothers, Ltd., P. & D. Colnaghi and Company, Ltd.; Diana Mary Reynolds Brewis, Newmarket, Suffolk, England; David [Kirkpatrick Este] Bruce (1898-1977), Under Secretary of State; John G. Forrest (1898-1982), financial-business editor, The New York Times; Frits Lugt, The Hague; Walter Muir Whitehill (1905-1978), Library of the Boston Athenaeum; Jean Barbey, Paris]
- European Travel 1953-1954, 2 folders (Box 1)
  [London dealers--P. & D. Colnaghi and Company, Ltd., Bernard Quaritch, Ltd., H. M. Calmann, Maggs Brothers, Ltd., Frederick B. Daniell and Son; Paris dealers--Jean Cailleux, Georges Heilbrun, Pierre Beres; Edward C[ronin] Lowe (1880-1958), Birmingham, England; Paul Cailleux, Paris; Philip Hofer (1898-1984), Harvard College Library, Cambridge, Massachusetts; Jean Barbey, Paris; David [Kirkpatrick Este] Bruce, United States Foreign Service, American Embassy, Paris; S[tephen] Bonsal White, Jr. (1922- ), Alex. Brown and Sons, Baltimore; letter of introduction from Mary Woodall (1901-1988), Oxford and Cambridge University Club, London; Geoffrey [Cecil Ryves] Eley (1904-1990), The British Drug Houses Ltd., London and East Bergholt Place, Suffolk, England; Arthur Rau, Yale Club, New York]
- European Travel 1953-1955, 3 folders (Box 2)
  [London dealers--P. & D. Colnaghi & Company, Ltd., Davies & Son Ltd., Bernard Quaritch Ltd., Crichton Brothers, Craddock & Barnard, B. T. Batsford Ltd., Myers & Company, Ltd., Elkin Mathews Ltd., W. R. Jeudwine; Paris dealers--Marc Loliee, Cailleux, Arthur Rau, Maggs Brothers; Mary Woodall, City Museum and Art Gallery, Birmingham, England; The Monaco Conference 1954; Jean Barbey, Paris; Diane Mary Reynolds Brewis; Anthony [Robert Alwyn] Hobson (1921- ), The Gladstone, New York; Reginald T. Townsend (1890-1977), French Institute and American Committee for Liberation from Bolshevism, New York; Hilda Johnstone (1882- ); Surrey, England; Charles E[li] Slatkin (1907-1977), New York; Sir Gerald Kelly (1879-1972), London re famous artists such as Raphael, Ary Scheffer, and Bougereau, working on his great winter exhibition, and J. R. Hale's book England and the Italian Renaissance; Osbert H[oward] Barnard (1903- ), London; Frances Kimmerle [Trees] (1916- ), Medallic Art Company, New York; Lady Judith Bateson, London; Percy Muir [Percival Horace Muir] (1894-1981), London; Karl D. Ackerman (1927- ), United States Mission to the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (USRO), Paris; report numbers one through twenty-two, June - September 1954 (daily log); Edith Calvert Peirce, Ladybird Forest,Edgewood, Maryland; Norman L[ewis] Torrey (1894-1980), Columbia University, New York; Ellen [Brashears] Watson Eager (1925- ), Watertown, New York]
- European Travel 1954-1956, 2 folders (Box 2)
  [London dealers--Charles W. Traylen, Guildford, P. & D. Colnaghi & Company, Ltd., Bernard Quaritch, Ltd.; Paris dealers - Xavier Piere, Librairie Lardanchet, Cailleux, Arthur Rau, Maggs Brothers, Les Librairies Flammarion, Etienne Rossignol, Marc Loliee; Hans Speidel (1897-1984), German Embassy, Washington, D. C.; Balzac Bulletin 1955; William H[obart] Royce (1878- ), "Les Jardies," Brooklyn; Jean Barbey, Paris; Arthur A[mory] Houghton, Jr. (1906-1990), New York; Yves Metman (1913- ), Societe des amis des Archives de France, Paris; Diana Mary Reynolds Brewis, Copenhagen, Denmark and Luneburg, North Germany; M[ilton] Chaikin (1915- ), Vaud, Switzerland; Louis C. Celestin, Alliance Francaise de Pittsburgh; report numbers one through seventeen 1955; Charles G. Proffitt (1896-1982), The Century Association; Lewis M. Lucas (1904- ), Stella Lucas Company, Hamilton, Ontario; [William] Vincent Astor (1891-1959), Newsweek Building, New York; W. L. Semcesen, Oslo, Norway; Mary Woodall, City Museum and Art Gallery, Birmingham, England; Anthony [Robert Alwyn] Hobston, Regent's Park, London; Frits Lugt, Paris; newspaper clipping photograph of Douglas Huntly and Winifred Macmillan Claude Gordon, Lelia Gordon, and Mr. and Mrs. John W. Avirett; L'Art du Livre aux Etats Unis au XXe Siecle, Paris 1945 memorabilia; Charles G. Proffitt, The Century Association, New York]
- European Travel 1955-1957, 2 folders (Box 2)
  [London dealers--Leggatt Brothers, P. & D. Colnaghi and Company Ltd., Bernard Quaritch Ltd., James Oakes, Davies & Son, G. Jetley, Crichton Brothers; Paris dealers--Arthur Rau, Marc Loliee, Georges Heilbrun, Cailleux; Diana Mary Reynolds Brewis, British Forces Post Office, near Dusseldorf, Germany, Dubrovnik, Yugoslavia and Luneburg, Germany; James Byam Shaw, London; H[ugh] F[rank] J[ohn] Leggatt (1925- ), London; Maryland History Notes November 1956 and articles re Benjamin Henry Latrobe (1764-1820); K[arl] T[heodore] Parker (1895-1992), The Ashmolean Museum, Oxford; Thomas [Sherrer Ross] Boase (1898-1974), Magdalen College, Oxford University; John [Waynflete] Carter; "Summary of France's Position on the Suez Issue...," October 10, 1956; David [Milton Kendall] McKibbin (1906-1978), Library of the Boston Athenaeum; report numbers one through twenty-seven, June - August 1956; Ian Forbes Fraser (1907- ), The American Library in Paris; Jacques Guignard (1912- ), Bibliotheque Nationale, Paris; Mary Woodall, City Museum and Art Gallery, Birmingham, England; Kenneth Holland (1907-1977), Institute of International Education, New York; [Arthur] Clive [Howard] Bell (1881-1964), Charleston, Firle, Sussex re his book Old Friends: Personal Recollections and Desmond Shawe-Taylor (1907- ); letters re residency training programs and post-graduate medical instruction from Gerard Roux-Dessarps, Paris, Edward L[ewis] Turner (1900-1960), American Medical Association, Chicago, Illinois, Francis Scott Smyth (1895-1972), University of California Medical Center, San Francisco, and, John E[arle] Bordley (1902-1993), Johns Hopkins Hospital, Baltimore; W[illiam] G[eorge] Constable (1887-1976), Curator of Paintings, Museum of Fine Arts; Charles G. Proffitt, The Century Association, New York; Sir Gerald Kelly, Portman Square, London re success on television and as a portrait writer since retirement as president of the Royal Academy; William Dwight Whitney (1899-1973), Highgate Village, London; Gerald J. McMahon (1907-1984), International Bar Association, New York; The Athenaeum, Pall Mall, London; John [Newenham] Summerson (1904-1992), Sir John Soane's Museum, London--letter of introduction for Douglas Huntly Gordon]
- European Travel 1957-1958, 2 folders (Box 2)
  [London dealers--Bernard Quaritch, Ltd., P. & D. Colnaghi & Company, Ltd., Leggatt Brothers, Davies & Son, Christy's of Kent, Ltd; Paris dealers--Etienne Rossignol, Cailleux, Arthur Rau, Marc Loliee; Jacques Guignard, Bibliotheque Nationale, Paris; Jan A. J. M. van Zuylen, Dordrecht, Holland; H[ugh] F[rank] J[ohn] Leggatt, London; Edward Croft-Murray (1907-1980), British Museum, London; A[nthony] R[obert] A[lwyn] Hobson, Sotheby and Company, London; Marc Chadourne (1895-1975), Connecticut College, New London; [Richard] Brinsley Ford (1908- ), Bryanston Square, London re works in progress; Jean Barbey, Paris; Zeiss Ikon AG, Stuttgart, Germany; Arthur A[mory] Houghton, Jr., New York; Hans Speidel, Chateau, Ailes des Princes, Fontainebleau, France; Mrs. Alexander [Elizabeth Clarke] Gordon, Huntly, Virginia re owning furniture designed by Stanford White (1853-1906) and buying it in 1900 a few years prior to his being killed by Harry K. Thaw; William C[attell] Trimble (1907-1996), Foreign Service of the United States of America, American Embassy, Bonn/Bad Godesberg, Germany; Adelaide L. Pohlman and Anne F. Buse, Charlecote House, Baltimore re household business]
- European Travel 1957-1959 (Box 2)
  [London dealers--Bernard Quaritch, Ltd.; Paris dealers--Marc Loliee, Arthur Rau; Robert G[raff] Merrick (1895- ), Munsey Building, Baltimore; Nicholas Rauch S. A., Geneva, Switzerland; Lucien Scheler, Librairie Thomas-Scheler, Paris; Jean Barbey, Paris; A[nthony] R[obert] A[lwyn] Hobson, London; Mrs. William Beach [Margaret] Olmsted, The American Library in Paris; Jacques Guignard, Bibliotheque Nationale, Paris; Charles G. Proffitt, The Century Association, New York; Adelaide L. Pohlman, Charlecote House, Baltimore re household business; resume of Douglas Huntly Gordon; Gerald J. McMahon, International Bar Association, New York; Marc Chadourne, Pepperbox Hill, Waterford, Connecticut; Alliance Francaise, Paris; Percy Muir [Percival Horace Muir], Elkin Mathews Ltd., Herts, England; John [Edward Austin] Jolliffe (1891-1964), British Museum, London]
- European Travel 1958-1960, 2 folders (Box 2)
  [London dealers--Bernard Quaritch, Ltd., P. & D. Colnaghi and Company, Ltd., Davies & Son Ltd., Arnold Wiggins and Sons, Ltd., Martin Breslauer, Thomas Agnew and Sons, Ltd., Charles J. Sawyer Ltd., Leggatt Brothers, Craddock & Barnard, H. Blairman & Sons Ltd.; Paris dealers--Fabius Freres, Cailleux, Arthur Rau, Marc Loliee, Georges Heilbrun; Jan A. J. M.van Zuylen, Dordrecht, Holland; W[illiam] G[eorge] Constable, Cambridge, Massachusetts; Louis Evrard, Editions du Rocher, Monaco; Stephen VanCortlandt Morris (1909-1984), Centre Culturel Americain, United States Information Service, Paris; Osbert [Howard] Barnhart (1903- ), London; Jozef Snoeck, Gent, Belgium; Paula Roth, Achern, Baden, Republic of West Germany; Julien Cain (1887-1974), Bibliotheque Nationale, Paris; [Dowrish] Evelyn [Louis] Joll (1925- ), London; H[ugh] F[rank] J[ohn] Leggatt, London; Bertram Newbury (1913- ), The Parker Gallery, London; John Snoeck, Berlin; R[oland] G[eorge] Hollins-Smith (1910- ), The Parker Gallery, London; Adelaide L. Pohlman, Anne F. Buse and Margaret Young, Charlecote House re household business; Gerard Roux-Dessarps, Paris; Ira J[ared] Porter (1896- ), The Louisville Trust Company, Louisville, Kentucky; Diana Mary Reynolds Brewis, England; Jean Barbey, Paris; James Byam- Shaw, London; Alliance Francaise, Paris; John Hayward (1905-1965), The Book Collector, London; Paula Roth, Achern, Baden, Republic of West Germany; typescript, "The Orchards Maintains the Best Tradition of its Past" and "Recollections of the Orchards"; John Marshall Butler (1897-1978), United States Senate]
- European Travel 1959-1961, 2 folders (Box 2)
  [London dealers--P. & D. Colnaghi and Company Ltd., Craddock & Barnard; Bernard Quaritch Ltd., Leggatt Brothers; Paris dealers--Bensimon, Marc Loliee, Arthur Rau; Frits Lugt, Paris; Jacques Guignard, Paris; Philippe Beguin, Geneva, Switzerland; Nicholas Rauch S. A., Geneva, Switzerland; J[ames] Rives Childs (1893-1987), Nice, Italy re Casanova Gleanings, The Secret of Casanova and love of Virginia; Herman Liebaers, Bibliotheque Royale de Belgique, Brussels, Belgium; newspaper photograph of Douglas Huntly and Winifred Macmillan Claude Gordon; Anne F. Buse, Margaret Young and Adelaide L. Pohlman, Charlecote House re household business; Hugh F[rank] J[ohn] Leggatt, London; Lucien Scheler, Librairie Thomas-Scheler, Paris; Maurice Zuber, Paris; Jean Barbey, Paris; The Athenaeum, Pall Mall, London; Cecil B[urton] Lyon (1903-1993), The Foreign Service of the United States of America, American Embassy, Paris re Madame Jacques Santu and aid for a group of Alsatian medical students, France and the Algerian problem, and General de Gaulle; Gerald J. McMahon, International Bar Association, New York]
- European Travel 1961-1967, 3 folders (Box 2)
  [London dealers--P. & D. Colnaghi and Company Ltd., Bernard Quaritch Ltd., Martin Breslauer, Craddock & Barnard, Maggs Brothers Ltd., B. T. Batsford Ltd., Davies & Son; Paris dealers--Arthur Rau, Etienne Rossignol, Saintyves, Marc Loliee; letters from Joseph D[avies] Tydings (1928- ), United States Senate, Daniel B[augh] Brewster (1923- ), United States Senate, [Edward] True Davis (1919- ), Treasury Department, J. Ross Prevost, and Bureau of Customs, Treasury Department re a customs controversy, assessment of duty, Treasury Department involvement concerning the transporting of Venetian glass; Gino Cenedese (1907-1973), Murano, Venice, Italy; Lucien Scheler, Librairie Thomas-Scheler, Paris; wedding invitation for Dominique Zuber and Jean Louis de Gourcuff; Herman Liebaers, Bibliotheque Royale de Belgique, Brussels, Belgium; Nicholas Rauch S. A., Geneva, Switzerland; P[ierre] B[ordeaux-] Groult (1916- ), Paris; Max [Andre] Terrier (1902- ), Musee National de la Cooperation Franco-Americaine; [George Hugh] Marquess of Cholmondeley (1919- ), Kensington Palace Gardens, London re Douglas Huntly Gordon visit to Houghton; Tarleton Winchester (1896-1967), United States Lines, London; Auguste Lambiotte, Brussels, Belgium; Mary Woodall, City Museum and Art Gallery, Birmingham, England; Diana Mary Reynolds Brewis, Monchengadbach, Republic of West Germany; John T. Hayes, The London Museum, Kensington Palace, London; David [Kirkpatrick Este] Bruce, Embassy of the United States of America, London; Julien Cain, Bibliotheque Nationale, Paris; Anthony [Robert Alwyn] Hobson, London; Maurice Zuber, Paris; Jean Barbey, Paris; Jacques Guignard, Bibliotheque Nationale, Paris; [Robert] Wyndham Ketton-Cremer (1906-1969), Felbrigg Hall, Norwich, England; John Hayward (1905-1965), Cheyne Walk, London; Laurence M[anuel] Lombard (1895- ), Hemenway & Barnes, Boston, Massachusetts; Jan A.J.M. van Zuylen, Dordrecht, Holland; Adelaide L. Pohlman and Anne F. Buse, Charlecote House re household business]
- European Travel 1962-1963, 2 folders (Box 3)
  [London dealers--P. & D. Colnaghi and Company Ltd., Lucien [Camille] Goldschmidt (1912-1992), Craddock & Barnard, Turnbull & Asser Ltd., Bernard Quaritch Ltd., Martin Breslauer, Maggs Brothers Ltd.; Paris dealers--Jean-Jacques Pauvert, Georges Heilbrun, Arthur Rau, Etienne Rossignol, Marc Loliee; John [Waynflete] Carter, Chelsea, London; The National Trust; The Travellers Club list of members; French brochures; International Bar Association; Gino Cenedese, Murano, Venice, Italy; Nicholas Rauch S. A., Geneva, Switzerland; John Grant Booksellers Ltd., Edinburgh; Osbert H[oward] Barnard, London; Brian Rawson, The Folio Society Limited, London; D[avid] M[cBeth] Sutherland (1883-1973), Taylor Institution, University of Oxford; John G. Matthews, Ocean City, Maryland; Courtenay E. Shaw (1915- ), Gloucestershire; David [Kirkpatrick Este] Bruce, Embassy of the United States of America, London; Thomas [Sherrer Ross] Boase, Magdalen College, Oxford University; Laurence Ewald (1907- ), Baltimore, Maryland; Albert Pages, Seine, France; Herman Liebaers, Bibliotheque Royale de Belgique, Brussels, Belgium; J[ames] Rives Childs; Jan A. J. M. van Zuylen, Dordrecht, Holland; Geoffrey [Edgar] Gorer (1905-1985), Sussex, England; John J[oseph] Slocum (1905- ), American Embassy, Cairo, Egypt]
- European Travel 1962-1963 (Box 3)
  [Paris dealers--Marc Loliee, Georges Heilbrun, Saintyves, Arthur Rau; Jan A.J.M. van Zuylen, Dordrecht, Holland re European reaction to John F. Kennedy's assasination; Leonce [Sylvain] Peillard (1898- ), Livres de France, Paris; William A[lexander] Jackson (1905-1964), Library of Harvard University, Cambridge, Massachusetts; Gordon W[illis] Jones (1915- ), Falmouth, Virginia; Barbara D. Sizer re routine legal matters; Robert G[raff] Merrick (1895- ), Baltimore, Maryland; Gordon N[orton] Ray (1915-1986), John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, New York]
- European Travel 1963-1964 (Box 23)
  [London dealers--Mallet at Bourdon House Limited, London; Paris dealers--Marc Loliee, Etienne Rossignol; Francis Aubert (1929- ), New York; Barbara D. Sizer re routine legal matters; Martin Eidelberg, New Brunswick, New Jersey; Julien Cain, Association Internationale de Bibliophile, Paris; Fred [Gentry] Frick (1932- ), Central, Y.M.C.A., Norfolk; Claude Tchou (1923- ), Tchou, Editeur, Paris; Auguste Lambiotte, Brussels, Belgium]
- European Travel 1965-1966, 2 folders (Box 3)